techlicious.com 2019-06-05

# Privacy Policy - Techlicious

Updated May 23, 2018.

Techlicious LLC ("Techlicious") respects your personal privacy and is committed to adhering to federal and state privacy laws and industry guidelines in order to protect you and your identity. This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") describes how we handle the personal information that you provide to us on this site (the "Techlicious Web Site" or the "Web Site"). This Privacy Policy applies only to the Techlicious Web Site and our Newsletters, not to any other related, affiliate or third party sites that may be accessible from here.

After reading this Privacy Policy, which is incorporated into and is a part of the Web Site's Terms of Use, you will know:

  * What information Techlicious collects from you;
  * How Techlicious uses your information;
  * What choices you have about how Techlicious treats your information;
  * How Techlicious protects your privacy;
  * What Techlicious does about children visiting the Web Site;
  * How you can contact Techlicious.

Please be sure to read this Privacy Policy before using the Web Site or submitting information to us. Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time and your continued use of the Web Site is acceptance of such changes, so please check this area periodically for updates to this Privacy Policy.

**_INFORMATION TECHLICIOUS COLLECTS FROM YOU_**

**Active Information Collection**

Like many other Web sites, we actively collect information from our visitors both by asking specific questions on the Web Site and by permitting you to communicate directly with us via email. Some of the information that you submit during the registration process may be personally identifiable (that is, information that can be uniquely identified with you, such as your name, business name, address, phone number, fax number, e-mail address, etc.).

When you visit the Web Site, we will not collect any personally identifiable information about you unless you provide it to us voluntarily. If you choose to register with the Web Site, during the registration process you will be asked for both personal and demographic information, some of which is required in order to complete the registration. We will inform you which information is optional. If you opt not to register with the Web Site, you still can visit the Web Site but may not be able to receive or view certain content such as our newsletter.

Techlicious does not have control over the privacy policies applied by any other party that you may disclose information to. Third party sites that are linked to from the Web Site are not under the control of Techlicious and we are not responsible for their content or privacy policies. If you would like information on any other party's privacy policy, you should contact that party directly, and we encourage you to do so.

**Passive Information Collection**  
As you navigate through a Web site, certain information can be passively collected (that is, gathered without you actively providing the information) using various technologies and means, such as navigational data collection. Like most Web site operators, we track IP addresses, use both session and persistent cookies, and assign Internet tags. Our system also automatically gathers information about the areas you visit on this site and collects operational information about the technology you use, such as your browser, type of computer, operating systems, Internet service providers and the domain name of the Web Site from which you linked to our site.

In addition, when you view the Web Site, we may store some information on your computer. This information will be in the form of a cookie or similar file and will help us in many ways. For example, cookies allow us to tailor our web site or advertisement to better match your interests and preferences. Most Internet browsers enable you to erase cookies from your computer hard drive, block all cookies, or receive a warning before a cookie is stored. Please refer to your browser instructions or help screen to learn more about these functions. Techlicious does not collect personally identifiable information automatically, but we may tie information collected automatically to your previously submitted personally identifiable information.

We passively collect information to understand what areas of the Web Site are most popular, which areas may require improvement and what technologies are being used by our visitors. This information helps us to update and improve the Web Site. We also use this information for security purposes, to detect and to block security breaches and to provide you with a safe online environment.

**_HOW TECHLICIOUS USES YOUR INFORMATION_**

Techlicious uses your personal information to enhance the operation of the Web Site and allow you to use all of its features.

Your contact information (e-mail addresses, name) and demographic information (e.g., age, location, income range) will be used for the purposes for which you supplied it to us (e.g., registering with the Web Site, receiving newsletter, etc.), to send you related notices or promotional materials and to respond to your comments or requests for information. If you direct comments to us or you request information from us, we may ask you to verify certain location information so that we can be assured that the response or information we provide is appropriate for that geographic location. We may also enhance or merge personally identifiable information with data obtained from third parties for the same purposes.

Techlicious will not give or sell your personally identifiable information to any outside organization for the organization's own use without your consent unless you explicitly give us permission to do so, for example, as part of an entry into a giveaway or through another promotion. Techlicious may disclose your personal information to reputable vendors that assist us in processing information or help us deliver services to our readers, including delivering interest-based ads on Techlicious.com or in our newsletters. These vendors are restricted from using the information for any purpose other than helping us to provide products and services. Techlicious, however, will have no liability for disclosure of information obtained due to errors in transmission or the unauthorized intervention of third parties.

We may sell or transfer anonymized (hashed) personal information collected online or through our newsletters to certain third parties, such as advertisers, who will use this data to serve ads that they believe are relevant to your interests.

Techlicious may provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales, online traffic patterns and related information to reputable third parties, but these statistics will not include any personally identifying information. Techlicious also will disclose any information that it is required to disclose by law or by an appropriate government authority.

Some of our advertisers may display ads on the Web Site that solicit, or contain technology to collect, information about our users. This information is collected and used by our advertisers, and is outside of our control. If you have any questions about an advertisement, you should contact the responsible advertiser directly.

Notwithstanding any other provision, we partner with third parties that collect information across various channels, including offline and online, for purposes of delivering more relevant advertising to you.  Our partners may place or recognize a cookie on your computer, device, or directly in our emails/communications, and we may share personal information with them if you have submitted such information to us, such as your name, postal address, email address, or device ID.  Our partners may link the nonpersonal information we share with them to the cookie stored on your browser or device, and they may collect information such as your IP address, browser or operating system type and version, and demographic or inferred-interest information.  Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes. For example, our partners may deliver an ad to you in your web browser based on a purchase you made in a physical retail store, or they may send a personalized marketing email to you based on the fact that you visited a particular website.  To learn more about interest-based advertising in general and to opt out, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. To opt-out of the use of your mobile device ID for targeted advertising, please see <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices>.

**_CHOICES YOU HAVE ABOUT HOW TECHLICIOUS USES YOUR INFORMATION_**  
We have created mechanisms to provide you with the following control over your information:

You may send us an e-mail message at [info@techlicious.com](mailto:info@techlicious.com) to request access to, correct or delete any personal information that you have provided to us. To protect your privacy, we will only respond to e-mail messages sent from the e-mail address you used to set up your account. Should you elect to have your information deleted, we will also delete your user account.

If you do not wish us to collect cookies, you may set your browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If you do so, please note that some parts of this site may then be inaccessible or not function properly. Users of our Web Site from EU countries may consent (or not) to receive cookies from the Web Site. See our EU Cookie Policy below for more information.

If you no longer wish to receive information or promotional materials from us by email you may opt out of receiving these communications. All of our emails will contain an opt-out or unsubscribe link at the bottom, which provides a fast, automated means of unsubscribing. You also may send us an email stating your request addressed to info@techlicious.com. However, because these requests must be handled manually, it may take 72 hours or longer to process the unsubscribe request.

You should review this Privacy Policy carefully, because if you do not agree with our practices, your ultimate choice is not to use the Web Site. Remember, by using any part of the Web Site, you accept and agree to our privacy practices. If we update this Privacy Policy, your continued use of the Web Site (following the posting of the revised Privacy Policy) means that you accept and agree to the terms of the revised Privacy Policy.

**_HOW TECHLICIOUS PROTECTS YOUR INFORMATION_**  
We work hard to protect your personal information. We use both technical and procedural methods to maintain the integrity and security of our databases, including the use of firewalls and restricted access to data.

The safety and security of your information also depends on you. If you have access to password-protected features, never share your password with anyone else, notify us promptly if you believe your password security has been breached, and remember to log off of this site or any connected social media platforms before you leave your computer. We further urge you to be careful about giving out personal information in public areas of this site like comment sections. When you provide information in these sections you do so at your own risk. The information you share may be viewed by any user of this site.

This site contains links to other websites operated by third parties that may be of interest to you. We cannot control these third party sites, which may collect personal information from you. When you follow a link and leave this site, you do so at your own risk.

**_WHAT TECHLICIOUS DOES ABOUT CHILDREN VISITING THE WEB SITE_**  
The Web Site is not intended for children under the age of 13. We will not knowingly collect information from site visitors in this age group. We encourage parents to talk to their children about their use of the Internet and the information they disclose online. If a child has provided us with personally identifiable information, a parent or guardian of that child may contact us via e-mail at [info@techlicious.com](mailto:info@techlicious.com) if they would like this information deleted from our records. We will use reasonable efforts to delete the child's information from our databases.

**_HOW YOU CAN CONTACT TECHLICIOUS_**  
If you have submitted personally identifiable information through the Web Site or an interactive advertisement, or if someone else has submitted your personally identifiable information through the Web Site or an interactive advertisement, and you would like to have that information deleted from our marketing databases, please contact us via email at [info@techlicious.com](mailto:info@techlicious.com). We will then use reasonable efforts to remove your personally identifiable information from our files. You also may contact us to request the personally identifiable information that Techlicious has collected about you through the Web Site or interactive advertisements. Techlicious will use reasonable efforts to supply you with this information and correct any factual inaccuracies in this information.

If you have any questions, comments or concerns about this Privacy Policy or the information practices of this site, please contact us at:

**Techlicious LLC Privacy Policy**  
**c/o Josh Kirschner**  
**500 East 77th Street  
New York, NY 10162**
